- They can't just march in here, can they?
- Not now. We've discovered how they got in.
- 他们不能进到这里来吧, 能吗 - 现在不能, 我们已经发现了他们是怎么进来的
Yes. They tunnelled into the storeroom.
是的, 他们打隧道进了储藏室
- Doctor, Mr. Hobson, come quickly!
- What is it?
- 博士, Hobson 先生, 快来！  - 什么事？
Moonbase, Moonbase
月球基地, 月球基地
- They've got our wavelength. We hear you.
- You are surrounded.
- 他们知道了我们的波长．我们能听到  - 你们已经被包围了
All resistance is useless.
所有抵抗都是徒劳的
You must open the entry port.
你们必须打开入口
Let me. You're wasting your time.
We've discovered your passageway and blocked it.
我来说, 你们是在浪费时间．我们已经发现了你们的通道, 堵上了
- You cannot enter now.
- Resistance is useless.
- 你们现在进不来了  - 抵抗是无用的
- Can they get in?
- I don't know, but I'm not stopping to find out.
- 他们能进来吗？  - 我不知道, 但我不会停止寻找的
- Get me Earth as quick as you can.
- Right.
- 赶紧给我联系地球, 越快越好 - 好的
Weather Control Moon calling Earth. Come in.
天气控制中心月球站呼叫地球, 请回话
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急情况！紧急情况！
There is a spaceship approaching from Earth.
有一首飞船正在接近, 是地球来的
It will arrive on the lunar surface in 15 minutes.
它将在１５分钟内到达月球表面
Immediate offensive action must be taken.
必须立即展开攻击行动了
They have blocked up our way into the base.
他们堵住了我们通往基地的路
Other methods to gain entry will be tried.
将尝试其它方式进入
The machine from Earth must first be destroyed.
地球来的机器必须先被摧毁
There are 14 minutes left.
只剩１４分钟了
Understood.
明白
Transmit control signal.
传送控制信号
You will listen to me and follow my instructions.
你将听我的, 服从我的指示
Here we are. I've brought some coffee to keep us awake.
来了, 我拿了一些咖啡, 让大家清醒清醒
- Without sugar this time, I hope?
- Of course. Don't remind me.
- 这次没有糖了吧, 但愿  - 当然, 别提这个
- Take some to the Doctor. He's in the Dome.
- Right.
- 给博士拿一点去, 他在穹顶里面  - 好的
You will now change field co-ordinates as instructed.
你现在要按照指示改变目的地坐标
Doctor, they've spotted it on the scanner - the relief ship.
博士, 可以在监视器上看到他们了 - 救援飞船
- Ben, where?   - Over here.   - Let's see.
- Ben, 哪儿？  - 在那儿   - 我们来看看
- Well?
- No doubt about it. I told you they would be on their way!
- 怎样？  - 没有疑问了, 我跟你说过他们已经在来的路上了
It's not far off.
不是太远了
Far off? It's coming in now off parking orbit.
It will be down in six minutes.
太远？它已经进了降落轨道．６分钟之内就会落地了
- Don't think you ought to warn them?
- Yes, the Cybermen will be waiting for them.
- 你不觉得应该警告他们吗？ - 是啊, 赛博人已经在等着他们呢
Don't worry. They've got their own warning system and weapons.
别担心．他们自己也有告警系统和武器
They'll blast the Cybermen and their spaceship
to kingdom come in about four minutes from now.
他们会把赛博人和他们的飞船炸会老家去, 还有大概４分钟
Come on!
快啊
It seems to move so slowly.
它好像移动得非常慢
- What are they doing?
- Looks like they've changed direction.
- 他们在干什么啊？  - 看起来好像他们改变了方向
They've changed into an escape orbit. Follow it.
他们切换到了脱离轨道．跟住
- It's going too fast. I can't keep up with it.
- Keep trying.
- 它在加速了, 我跟不住了  - 继续尝试
- I can't hold it. It's accelerating too fast.
- Look out man. You're on the sun.
- 我没法跟住了, 它加速太快了  - 小心啊朋友, 你已经在往太阳飞了
- That's where it's heading.
- The acceleration is.. it's gigantic!
- 它就是在往那儿飞  - 加速度..也太大了！
- Get R/T contact with the ship.
- It's no good, sir...the doppler effect...It's going too fast.
- 用无线电联系飞船  - 没用的, 头儿...多普勒效应...它跑得太快了
They've had it, I'm afraid.
他们已经跑不了了, 恐怕
- The sun...
- Yes.
- 太阳...  - 是的
Will somebody please tell us what it all means?
谁能不能告诉我这都是什么意思？
The rocket has been deflected towards the sun.
Nothing can save them now.
火箭已经飞偏了, 在往太阳飞去．现在没谁能救他们了
- Save them? What are you talking about?
- From plunging into the sun.
- 救他们？你在说什么啊？  - 阻止他们飞向太阳
But the sun's millions of miles away.
但太阳有数百万英里之远呢
Once they get into the sun's gravity belt,
they can't change course.
一旦他们进入了太阳的引力范围, 他们就改变不了航线了
It may take a week but they'll end up there.
大概需要一个星期, 但他们最终会在那儿
What on earth could have caused it?
到底是什么东西导致了这个？
The rocket was deflected off course, but why, and how?
火箭当然是被导偏了, 但是为什么, 怎么搞得？
Deflected?
导偏？
- Yes, of course. The Gravitron!
- Have the Cybermen got a gravity weapon, do you think?
- 是了, 当然, 引力创！  - 赛博人有引力武器吗, 你觉得？
- No, they haven't, but we have.
- You're not suggesting...?
- 不, 他们没有, 但我们有  - 你不是想说...？
The only one way that rocket could be deflected
into the sun... was this very room.
火箭飞被导向太阳的唯一方法...就在这个房间里！
I see what you mean.
我知道你的意思了
Of course - the Gravitron.
当然了 - 引力创
- Benson! He must...
- I said he'd been on duty too long.
- Benson! 他肯定... - 我说过他值班时间太长了
If it IS Benson...
如果的确是 Benson...
It's Evans!
是 Evans!
- He was in the medical room.
- The Cybermen have control of them again.
- 他在医务室啊 - 赛博人又控制了他们
- And the other men in there?
- They may not be affected yet.
- 那里的其他人呢？  - 他们可能还未受影响
Get down to the medical room.
Barricade the door with everything you can find.
赶紧去医务室, 用所有能找到的东西把门堵上
- Keep them in there at all costs!  - Right.
- 不惜一切代价把他们控制在里面  - 好
What is he doing in there?
他在那里面做什么？
Look at the field reactors. We must get back control soon.
看看域反应器(?), 我们必须赶紧夺回控制权
He could flood half of Europe
if he keeps the Gravitron aligned with spring tides.
他可能都淹了半个欧洲了，如果他一直让引力创定在涨潮位置的话
That settles it. We'll have to rush him.
Get those weapons out.
就这样定了，我们得赶紧把他赶出去。把那些武器拿出来
Resistance is useless.
抵抗是没有用的
All further ships from Earth will be deflected.
后面再有从地球来的飞船也会转向
Open the air lock to us.
为我们打开气闸
If you do not, we shall destroy the base,
如果你们不打开，我们将摧毁基地
and you will be eliminated.
你们将会被消灭
Can you hear me?
你们能听到我？
Everything you have said
in the past half-hour has been overheard.
你们在过去半小时内说的话，全都听见了
You can hear this, too, then: we're not done yet,
and we'll fight you to the last man.
你还能听到这个：咱们没完，我们会跟你们战斗到最后一个人
- You'll never get inside this base!
- We are in it already.
- 你们永远进不了这个基地  - 我们已经进来了
They've punctured the dome!
他们打穿了穹顶！
The oxygen masks.
Everyone take a mask over there!
氧气面罩！所有人都那儿去带上氧气面罩！
I hope that we don't lose too much oxygen.
我期望我们没丧失多少氧气
- Can we patch it, do you think?
- We can try.
- 我们能补上吧，你说呢  - 我们试试
Give me a hand off with this.
给我搭把手
Doctor, I can't breathe.
博士，我不能呼吸了
Thank heavens! I can breathe again.
感谢上天！我又能呼吸了
Oh, no!
噢，不！
- What can we patch it with?
- Nothing.
- 我们能拿什么来堵？  - 没啥
Wait...
等等...
Over there.
那边
Slide it to me but don't let go of it.
把它滑给我，别放手
We have to do it in one action. No second chance. Are you ready?
我们必须一次搞定，没有第二次机会。准备好了吗？
Now!
走！
Stopped them for the moment.
暂时阻止他们了
- I wonder for how long.
- Let's have a look.
- 我在想能有多久 - 我们看看吧
Polly! Are you all right?
Polly！你没事吧？
Yes.
是的
- Where's that air coming from?
- Reserve tanks of oxygen.
- 那些空气哪里来的？ - 预备的氧气瓶
- Why couldn't we have had those before?
- And lose all our oxygen?
- 之前为什么没有？ - 你是说失去我们所有的氧气？
I see.
我明白了
- It's so quiet!  - Yes, it is, isn't it?
- 好安静啊！  - 是的，真安静，是吧？
The Gravitron's stopped!
引力创停掉了！
Quick. Before he comes to. Ben! Jamie!
快！在他醒过来之前. Ben! Jamie!
Joe!
We've barricaded the sick bay with half the chairs and tables in the base, but it won’t hold them for ever.
我们堵住了医务室，用了基地半数的椅子和桌子，但没法永远挡住他们
- Well done. - Here's another one for you.
- 干得好  - 这个你来
- What do we do with him, Doctor?
- That's your problem.
- 我们拿他怎么办，博士  - 那是你的事
Just make sure he doesn’t come back here for a while.
只是要确保短时间内他不能回到这里来
I’ll be after a job as a copper when I get
back to 1966!
等我回到1966年，我要去找个当警察的职业干干
Mr Hobson, I've got an idea.
Hobson 先生，我有了个想法
- Doctor, what do you make of this?
- Made by a laser beam, I think.
- 博士，你觉得这是怎么造成的  - 激光束，我想是
- Is there anything known to science the Cybermen haven't got?
- They haven’t got a Gravitron. Or they wouldn't be after yours.
科学上已知的东西里面有没有什么赛博人没掌握的？
他们还没有引力创，否则他们不会来抢你们的
We'll have to stand guard here
with their cyberguns.
Not much use. They're getting
reinforcements. Looks like another spaceship.
没多大用. 他们有了增援. 看样子是又来一艘飞船
Just there.
就在那儿
Another one!
又来一个！
We have brought
reinforcements with other weapons.
我们带来了增援和其它武器
You have one chance.
You must open the entry port.
你们有一次机会. 你们必须打开入口
You cannot stop us now.
You will all be completely destroyed.
现在你们阻挡不了我们了. 你们全部都会被完全消灭
- What does he mean, other weapons?
- We'll soon find out. You stay here. I must report this to Mr. Hobson.
他什么意思，“其它武器”？
我们很快就能弄清楚. 你在这里待着. 我必须向 Hobson 先生报告这个
I shall count to ten.
我将数到十
If you still stupidly remain silent, we shall fire.
如果你们仍然愚蠢地保持沉默，我们将开火
One...
一
- Hurry! They've got another weapon. They're going to ...
- Yes, I know. There it is.
- 快！他们有了另外一个武器，他们要...
- 是的，我知道，就在那儿
Everybody take cover. Get down, all of you! Doctor!
所有人都躲起来. 你们全都蹲下！博士！
- Is the Gravitron still switched on?  - Yes.
- 引力创还开着吗？  - 是的
Then I shall certainly stay here.
那我就一定还得留在这里
.. nine, ten... Fire!
...九，十...开火！
Again. Fire.
再来，开火！
- What happened?
- It just deflected over the dome.
- 什么情况？ - 它刚才转弯从穹顶上飞过去了
- Are you all right?  - Yes.
- 你没事吧？  - 没事
- The Gravitron deflected it. The force field.
- Yes. And that gives me an idea.
- 引力创弹歪了它，力场的作用  - 是的，这给了我一个主意
What are they doing now?
他们现在在干什么？
They're packing it away.
他们在收拾走人
What will they cook up next?
他们下一步想炮制什么？
How far down can this be aimed? Can it be
brought to bear on the surface of the moon?
这个最低可以瞄准哪里？能否牵引到对准月球表面？
- I see!  - Well...
- 我明白了  - 这个...
- Has it ever been tried?  - No, but we shall try.
- 试过这样吗？  - 没，但我们得试试
- With Evans gone, the Gravitron is all yours.
- Je m'en occupe!
- 现在 Evans 走了，引力创归你了 - 我会处理好的（法语）
Any further down, and the field may affect the base.
再低一点，力场就会影响基地了
- What does that matter now?
- Ah, I suppose you're right.
- 到现在了，那又有什么关系   - 啊，我想你是对的
- Get someone to stand by that window
and relay instructions direct to Benoit.
- Right!
找个人站到那个窗户旁边，将指令转述给 Benoit
- He's ready.  - Start moving the probe down.
- 他就绪了  - 开始向下移动探测器
- That's as far as it will go.
- What?
- 最多也就能到这个位置了
- 什么？
But it's way over their heads.
但高出他们的头太多了
There's one chance. We'll try bringing it down by hand.
只有一次机会，我们得用手把它拉下来
- Is this still switched off?
- No, No.. Yes, of course.
- 这个仍然是关着的吗？   - 不，不，对了，当然
- It won't go.
- All your weight. Once more.
- 它没动  - 用上全部力气，再来一次
- It's no use. It won't shift.
- Ah, stupid of me! Of course it won't!
- 没用，它一动不动  - 啊，我真蠢，当然它不会动了
- Why?
- The angular cut-out. It's obvious!
- 为什么？  - 角度阻断器，很显然
There's got to be a safety cut-out
on the angle of the probe.
探测器的角度必须得有一个安全阻断器
Otherwise, it might affect the whole base./
否则，它就会影响整个基地
That's done it. Stand back. Benoit can do it now.
这下可以了。往后站。Benoit 现在可以操作了
Switch on!
现在启动！
Well, that's taken care of the Cybermen!
好了，它可以照料赛博人了
We've got to get this Gravitron in operation as fast as we can!
我们得尽快让引力创重新运转起来！
- I'm so sorry we damaged it.  - What? Oh, yes...
- 很抱歉我们毁坏了它  - 什么？噢，是的...
Nils, rig up a temporary aerial. Call up Space Control.
Nils, 架一个临时天线，联系控制中心
Tell Rinberg we'll be operational in about two hours.
It's the best we can do.
告诉 Rinberg 我们将在大约两小时后恢复运作。最好我们也就能这样了
Two hours! That's all we've got to
get the world's weather under control again.
两小时，那是我们能有的时间，要让地球天气重新处于掌控之中
Benoit, take charge of your side.
And, Doctor... What the...
Benoit, 负责你那边的事情。而博士...怎么...
It's just as well. We've enough madmen here already!
这样也行吧，我们这里疯子已经够多了
I want to see your first weather plot in two minutes!
我期望在两分钟之内见到你的天气运行图
Come on, boys.
加油，小伙子们
Doctor, look.
博士，看
- Could that be them?  - Possibly.
- 会是他们吗？  - 很可能
And I hope it's the last we see of them.
我期望这是我最后一次看见他们
There we are. In perfect flight.
好啦，进入完美的飞行了
- Yes, and look what happened last time!
- Just a bumpy landing. It won't happen again.
- 是啊，看看上次都发生了什么！
- 只是着陆有点颠簸，不会再发生了
- I know.
- What you're up now?
- 我知道  - 你又在干什么？
- Let's have a look at the Time Scanner. - The what?
- 我们来看看时间扫描仪  - 看什么？
The Time Scanner. Instead of showing where we are,
it gives you a glimpse of the future.
时间扫描仪。不是显示我们在哪儿，而是让你瞥一眼未来
The second sight? Very dangerous.
第二视觉？这太危险了
Nonsense! I haven't used it very much.
It's not very reliable, as you can see.
胡说！我用它的次数不多，它不是太可靠，你们可以看到
Doctor...
博士...
Look!
快看！
Next: The Macra Terror
下一集：大螯的恐怖
（此集故事原有视频全部丢失, 但音频尚保留完整．BBC已经在采用动画方式
重新制作该故事, 计划于2019年３月发布）